<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>JIPCAD Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>JIPCAD Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://JIPCAD.github.io/img/nome.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Striking Bell]]></title>
        <id>Striking Bell</id>
        <link href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog/2022/12/7/Toby"/>
        <updated>2022-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: this project is the subject of the Level 5 Putting It All Together tutorial and can be constructed for yourself by following the steps there.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Note: this project is the subject of the Level 5 Putting It All Together tutorial and can be constructed for yourself by following the steps there.</h4><p>This was my most difficult project, as I wanted to stretch the limits of JIPCAD somewhat. Most of my previous models--and indeed what JIPCAD is primarily intended for--is static depictions of geometric objects. My goal was to build a bell whose clapper would travel back and forth in a pendulum arc, and upon striking the side of the bell would cause lightning to shoot out the side, indicating noise.</p><p>I started by building the yoke from simple rectangles, and added some colors to my included Surfaces file (see <a href="/docs/common-include-files">Common Include Files</a>) to do so--that&#x27;s the Brown, Orange, and Zinc you can see towards the bottom of the file.</p><p>The bell was a little more difficult; the bottom was a simple torus, but the sides and cap of the bell were two shapes for which we didn&#x27;t have generators--a paraboloid and a section of a hyperboloid, that had to intersect fairly seamlessly.</p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/paraboloid.png" alt="paraboloid"/></p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/Hyperboloid1.png" alt="hyperboloid"/></p><p>These I built with general surfaces, which are highly flexible and I recommend to anyone with a specific shape in mind that has an equation (e.g. z = x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2) but no generator. I added a cylinder and clapper to make a sphere, set them to move along an arc using $time and cosine functions, and ended up with the bell below:</p><p><img src="/img/bell-front.png" alt="bellfront"/></p><p><img src="/img/bell-side.png" alt="bellside"/></p><p>Unfortunately, general surfaces do not have any thickness the same way a torus with radius 3 does, so I ended up with problems:</p><p><img src="/img/bell-clapper-through-side.png" alt="bellintersecting"/></p><p>After some fiddling, I got that out of the way, but now I had a bigger problem: how could I make lightning appear on only one side of the bell at a time, only when the clapper struck, and make it disappear after striking? JIPCAD didn&#x27;t support a max or if statement, and while the general surfaces do, they don&#x27;t allow the use of $time or user parameters. <br/>
After a significant struggle, I landed on time-based scaling: that is, if I could have the shape expand to full size when the clapper hit the bell, and otherwise be shrunk down to an infinitesimal point, I could model my desired behavior. After some muddling about with finding the correct scaling function (it was sin and cos^128), I finally finished the bell! Tragically I can&#x27;t show a full gif--it would ruin the reveal too thoroughly, I&#x27;ll leave that for after you build it for yourself. The full code is available for yourself at the end of the Putting It All Together <a href="/docs/tutorial/putting-together">tutorial</a>, enjoy!</p><p><img src="/img/Bell-lightning.png" alt="bell-lightning"/></p><p><img src="/img/bell-lightning-left.png" alt="bell-lightning-left"/></p><p><img src="/img/bell-lightning-right.png" alt="bell-lightning-right"/></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Yegian</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/tobyegg</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celtic Knot]]></title>
        <id>Celtic Knot</id>
        <link href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog/2022/10/29/Toby"/>
        <updated>2022-10-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Celtic Knot was one of my biggest projects and one of the ones I'm most proud of. It involved taking the Celtic knot from the image below:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Celtic Knot was one of my biggest projects and one of the ones I&#x27;m most proud of. It involved taking the Celtic knot from the image below:</p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/celtic-knot-source.png" alt="img"/></p><p>and turning it into an interactive mathmatical knot. The design followed multiple iterations, first with a set of two b-splines multiplied over each identical quarter of the knot. The effect was very &quot;loopy&quot;, and while interesting was not what I had intended.</p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/loopyknot1.png" alt="loopyknot"/></p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/loopyknot2.png" alt="loopyknot2"/></p><p>I then attempted to make the curve sharper at its points and simpler in construction. Ultimately, with some help from Prof. Sequin, I redefined my knot as a set of four short b-splines (it turns out a new one was needed for each sharp corner) multiplied over each eighth of the knot. The result was quite accurate:</p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/celtic-knot-finished.png" alt="goodknot"/></p><p>And for good measure, I then added a second identical knot and parametrized every dimension I could think of, allowing for manipulation of the design into very fun shapes.</p><p><img src="/img/blogpics/knot-manipulated1.png" alt="funknot1"/>
<img src="/img/blogpics/knot-manipulated2.png" alt="funknot2"/>
<img src="/img/blogpics/knot-manipulated3.png" alt="funknot3"/></p><p>At some point, I hope to export some of these models and 3D print these awesome shapes.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Yegian</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/tobyegg</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bowtie Sweep]]></title>
        <id>Bowtie Sweep</id>
        <link href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog/2022/9/14/Toby"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is one of my first projects in JIPCAD, before I was very familiar with sweeps or (apparently) taking screenshots.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of my first projects in JIPCAD, before I was very familiar with sweeps or (apparently) taking screenshots.</p><p><img src="/img/BowtieSweep.PNG" alt="Bowtie Sweep"/></p><p>The blue outline on the left shows the intended path of the sweep, a cube with only one line connecting the top and bottom faces, and the right shows the actual sweep path. I was new at using B-splines when working on this project, and so struggled with understanding why the two weren&#x27;t the same, as well as why my swept polygon was broken in several places and why half of my bowtie was black (meaning on the &quot;inside&quot; of the shape).<br/>
<!-- -->Still, it was an informative project that pushed me to design more intracite sweeps and later knots, and I was impressed at what I could come up with given very little experience or work in JIPCAD.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Yegian</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/tobyegg</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>welcome</id>
        <link href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the JIPCAD Exhibition Page, you are welcomed to post any of your exbihition here for the inspiration and entertainment of the whole JIPCAD community!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the JIPCAD Exhibition Page, you are welcomed to post any of your exbihition here for the inspiration and entertainment of the whole JIPCAD community!</p><p><img src="./lumpysphere.gif" alt="Docusaurus Plushie"/></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Xinyu Zhang</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Xinyuzhangg</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xinyu Zhang]]></title>
        <id>Xinyu-Zhang</id>
        <link href="https://JIPCAD.github.io/blog/Xinyu-Zhang"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my first blog for the JIPCAD!!!🌈]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first blog for the JIPCAD!!!🌈
I love JIPCAD!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Xinyu Zhang</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Xinyuzhangg</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>